Akshay Sushir

Software Engineer

akshay.sushir99@gmail.com • +919998268272

https://www.linkedin.com/in/akshay-sushir-280324119/ • https://github.com/axaysushir •

Summary

Full-Stack developer with hands-on experience in **designing**, **developing & implementing** applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. **Contributor of open-source NLP library Compromise**. Once in a while, I write blog articles about coding, programming tips & tricks and Cloud computing to share my experience & help software developers.

Skills

JavaScript • Node.js • Git • Python • React • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Aws

Work Experience

Application Engineer

May 2022 - present

Sage Intacct Inc. • Full-time

Bangalore, India

Technologies: JavaScript

Build Enginnering Release Management Tools.

Software Engineer

Jul 2020 - May 2022 • 1 yr 10 mos

Ampyard Pvt. Ltd. • Full-time

Bangalore, India

Technologies: JavaScript • Node.js • React with redux • Amazon Web Services • PostgreSQL

- Developed full-stack web applications using cloud computing, real-time data processing, data storage,
 ML, and AI to solve challenging problems.
- Develop user interfaces in **React**, design & build **Serverless** backend **APIs** in **Node.js & AWS Lambda**.
- Integrate **Firebase authentication** with salesforce auth for React app.
- Design & Integrate Stripe payment gateway for subscriptions & billing and sync with PostgreSQL DB.
- Deployment of application on AWS S3 & Lambda. Integrate AWS SES for email communication within apps.

Projects

Facequest Jul 2020 – Apr 2021 • 9 mos

Technologies: Python • Javascript node.js • React • Amazon lambda • Express JS

Facequest is **facial recognition SaaS platform** that uses **AI & machine learning** to detect faces which is useful for securing ATM, Contactless Identity verification, customer onboarding, paperless KYC etc.

NotesAlly - Salesforce AI Sales Assistant

Apr 2021 - May 2022 • 1 yr 1 mo

Technologies: Javascript node.js • React with redux • Amazon lambda • Amazon s3 • Firebase

NotesAlly is an **Al sales assistant** for the Salesforce platform which interacts with Salesforce to update tasks, calls & opportunities etc. to save users time and let them manage activities on the go.

Educations

Bachelor's degree: Electrical Engineering

Jun 2011 – Jun 2015 • 4 yrs

Gujarat Technological University

Ahmedabad, India

Grade/GPA: 7.1

Certifications & Awards

Full-Stack Web Developer Bootcamp - Udemy	Nov 2019
Full Stack MERN Bootcamp - Learncodeonline	May 2020

Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)